Guide to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Carnegie Endowment for International Peace Records,
1910-1954.
Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.
335 linear ft (678 boxes, 536 volumes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078585
Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, established by Andrew Carnegie in 1910, is a private, nonprofit organization dedicated to advancing cooperation between nations and promoting active international engagement by the United States. The files document the activities of the New York and Washington Offices of Carnegie Endowment for International Peace from 1910 until 1954, as well as the founding, administration, and activity of the Centre Europeen (CEIP Paris Office) and the work of the Carnegie Endowment in Europe in 1911-1940
Historical Note
Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, established by Andrew Carnegie in 1910, is a private, nonprofit organization dedicated to advancing cooperation between nations and promoting active international engagement by the United States. Carnegie selected 28 trustees who were leaders in American business and public life; among them were Harvard University president Charles W. Eliot; philanthropist Robert S. Brookings; former Ambassador to Great Britain Joseph H. Choate; former Secretary of State John W. Foster; former president of MIT and then-president of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching Henry S. Pritchett; and Carnegie Institution of Washington president Robert S. Woodward. He chose longtime adviser Elihu Root -Senator from New York, former Secretary of War and of State, and future Nobel Peace Prize recipient- to be the Endowment's first president. The Endowment was initially organized into three divisions: the Division of Economics and History to study the causes and impact of war, the Division of Intercourse and Education to promote international understanding and cooperation, and the Division of International Law to aid in the development of international law and dispute settlement.
A European Centre and advisory board, set up in Paris as part of the Division of Intercourse and Education, was initially headed by Baron Paul d'Estournelles de Constant, founder and president of the Association for International Conciliation. The Library of the Centre Europeen was founded in 1913 in order to establish a collection of works on international law, politics, economics, government, and social science. During the interwar period, the Endowment revitalized efforts to promote international conciliation, financed reconstruction projects in Europe, supported the work of other organizations, and founded the Academy of International Law at the Hague. Endowment publications of the interwar period included the unprecedented 22-volume Classics of International Law, and the 150-volume Economic and Social History of the World War.
In 1925, Nicholas Murray Butler, also a Nobel Prize recipient, succeeded Elihu Root as president of the Endowment. Over the next 20 years he promoted his vision of international cooperation in business and politics. Among his other accomplishments, he was instrumental in fashioning the Kellogg-Briand no-war pact of 1928. The activities of CEIP European Centre were almost completely suspended during the Nazi occupation of Paris. In 1954 the Centre moved to Geneva. Following World War II and Butler's retirement, the Endowment's three divisions were consolidated under the direction of President Joseph E. Johnson. John Foster Dulles led the board. For the next two decades the Endowment conducted research and public education programs on a range of issues, particularly relating to the newly created United Nations and the future of the postwar international legal system. The Endowment provided diplomatic training for some 250 foreign service officers from emerging nations and published International Conciliation, a leading journal in the field.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, memoranda, financial documents, minutes, book and lecture typescripts, printed matter, reports, press releases, news clippings, posters, architectural plans, and photographs document the activities of the New York and Washington Offices of Carnegie Endowment for International Peace from 1910 until 1954, as well as the founding, administration, and activity of the Centre Europeen (CEIP Paris Office) and the work of the Carnegie Endowment in Europe in 1911-1940. The CEIP records are most complete for the 1940-1945 period, while some documentation from the post-war period was retained by the Endowment. The collection does not include any records on grants given by the CEIP. Grant files and post-1954 materials are still with the Endowment in Washington, DC.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in nine series and several subseries.
Series I. Secretary's Office
Subseries I.A. Correspondence
Subseries I.B: Annual report materials,1931-1949
Subseries I.C: Board of Trustees, 1910-1943
Subseries I.D: Depository Libraries, 1936-1949
Subseries I.E: Financial, 1910-1949
Subseries I,F: Incorporation of CEIP, 1928-1930
Subseries I.G: Library of CEIP, 1925-1950
Subseries I.H: Officer files and correspondence, 1908-1951
Subseries I.I: Other Carnegie Organizations
Subseries I.J: Physical Plant-Building and Grounds, 1924-1949
Subseries I.K: Postwar and Peace plans, 1912-1943
Subseries I.L: Publications
Subseries I.M: Publicity and Press Releases, 1914-1946
Subseries I.N: Reports for Trustee Information
Subseries I.O: Second Pan American Scientific Congress
Series II: Division of Economics of History, 1910-1930
Subseries II.A: General Correspondence, 1910-1922
Subseries II.B: Economic and Social History of the World War, 1921-1930
Series III: Division of Intercourse and Education
Subseries III.A: General correspondence, 1910-1934
Subseries III.B: Topical volumes, 1910-1940
Subseries III.C: European Centre (Centre Européen)
Subseries III.D: London Office, 1935-1947
Series IV: Division of International Law
Subseries IV.A: General
Subseries IV.B: Classics of International Law, 1910-1926
Subseries IV.C: Conferences
Subseries IV.D: Fellowships, 1925-1935
Subseries IV.E: Meetings, 1928-1947
Subseries IV.F: Promotion, 1923-1949
Subseries IV.G: Reports and publications, 1936-1948
Subseries IV.H: Report on Teaching of International Law, 1913-1921
Series V: Conferences and Institutes
Series VI: Organizations
Series VII: Projects
Subseries VII.A: Academy of International Law at the Hague
Subseries VII.B: Aid to Refugees, 1926, 1933-1948
Subseries VII.C: American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1918-1922
Subseries VII.D: American Library Association, 1925-1947
Subseries VII.E: American Library in Paris, 1923-1947
Subseries VII.F: Armistice Day Programs, 1933-1939
Subseries VII.G: Atomic Energy Committee, 1945-1949
Subseries VII.H: Beyond Victory Radio Programs, 1943-1948
Subseries VII.I: Biblioteca Interamericana, 1916-1947
Subseries VII.J: Canadian American Relations, 1933-1948
Subseries VII.K: Chaplain, The, 1945-1947
Subseries VII.L: Chautauquas, 1915-16
Subseries VII.M: Civil Aviation, 1944
Subseries VII.N: Commission to study the organization of peace, 1940-1948
Subseries VII.O: Committee to Aid Czechoslovakia
Subseries VII.P: Committee on International Economic Policy
Subseries VII.Q: European Relief after World War I, 1916-1927, 1939
Subseries VII.R: European Tariff Walls Map, 1929-1933
Subseries VII.S: Films: "Made in USA" and others, 1927, 1937, 1944-1949
Subseries VII.T: Inter-American Affairs, 1916-1949
Subseries VII.U: International Conciliation, 1907-1947
Subseries VII.V: International Mind Alcoves, 1922-1946
Subseries VII.W: International Relations Centers, 1925-1948
Subseries VII.X: International Relations Clubs, 1927-1948
Subseries VII.Y: International Visits
Subseries VII.Z: Library aid and special gifts of books
Subseries VII.AA: Louvain Library
Subseries VII.BB: Notes and Forecasts, 1947-1949
Subseries VII.CC: Orient
Subseries VII.DD: Rejected Projects, 1952
Subseries VII.EE: Stresemann Memorial, 1930-1931
Subseries VII.FF: United States Summer Schools, 1915
Subseries VII.GG: Vatican Library, 1926-1937
Subseries VII.HH: Visiting Carnegie Professors, 1927-1947
Series VIII. CEIP Library
Subseries VIII.A: CEIP reports and publications
Subseries VIII.B: Other publications
Subseries VIII.C: Clippings re the Endowment
Series IX. Oversize Material
Subjects
Geneva Research Center.; International Labour Organization.; League of Nations.; United Nations.; Andrew Carnegie.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.; Davis, Malcolm W. (Malcolm Waters), b. 1899.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.; Estournelles de Constant, Paul-Henri-Benjamin Balluet, baron d', 1852-1924.; Hiss, Alger.; Johnson, Joseph E. (Joseph Esrey), 1906-; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1888-1957.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.; Florinsky, Michael T., 1894-1981.; Freud, Sigmund, 1856-1939.; Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Leacock, Stephen, 1869-1944.; Masters, Edgar Lee, 1868-1950.; Mili︠u︡kov, P. N. (Pavel Nikolaevich), 1859-1943.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Wister, Owen, 1860-1938.; Peace--Societies, etc.; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations.; Endowments--United States.; Endowments--New York (State)--New York.; Endowments--France--Paris.; Endowments--Officials and employees.; Humanitarianism.; International relations--Research.; Philanthropists.
Acquisition
1953 M-53 Carnegie Endowment Gift
Alternate Formats
Parts of collection are available on microfilm. Please consult the curator for details.
Gift of the Carnegie Endowment, 1953 & 1954.
Related Collections at Columbia
James T. Shotwell Papers
John Bates Clark Papers
Nicholas Murray Butler Papers
Malcolm Waters Davis Papers
- Series I. Secretary's Office
  (137 volumes, 105 boxes)
  The Secretary, chief administrative officer of the Endowment, conducted the general correspondence and signed all instruments in the name of the corporation. In addition to its general administrative duties, the Secretary served as the secretary of the Board of Trustees and of the Executive Committee; edited and distributed the Endowment's Year Book (annual report); supervised the production, free distribution, and sales of most of the Endowment's publications; and oversaw the operation of the Endowment's library in its Washington office. (Source: Carnegie Endowment for International Peace: Summary of Organization and Work. Washington DC: CEIP, 1941 (pp. 16-17.).
  The Secretary's Office records (Series I) contain general correspondence files, annual report materials, trustee minutes and files, financial records, officer files and correspondence, a large collection of mostly unsolicited peace plans and proposals, publicity files, reports prepared for Trustee information, and files relating to other Carnegie organizations. Within this series, specific Endowment activities and program areas are documented by files on its depository library program, its incorporation in 1930 its library, its physical plant and offices, its publishing program, and its role in the Second Pan-American Conference.
  - Subseries I.A. Correspondence
    (9 boxes, 133 volumes)
    - Subsuberies I.A.1. Cataloged correspondence
      (1 box)
      - Addams, Jane. To N.M. Butler, 8 Jan 1931 (Box 1)
      - Adenauer, Conrad. To Shotwell, 30 Jan 1950 (Box 1)
      - Austin, Warren R.
        - To Alger Hiss, 20 Sept 1947 (Box 1)
        - To Joseph E. Johnson, 17 July 1950 (Box 1)
      - Baruch, Bernard M. To N.M. Butler, 10 Jan 1925 18 Nov. 1938 (2 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Benes, Eduard. To N.M. Butler, 4 April 1922 (Box 1)
      - Bernhard, Prince of the Netherlands. To Joseph E. Johnson, 5 June 1952 (Box 1)
      - Bryan, William Jennings. To Henry S. Haskell, 2 April 1925 (Box 1)
      - Buck, Pearl S.
        Available on microfilm (#91-2094-2). Originals not available for consultation.
        - To Maurice Sherman, 25 April 1944 (Box 1)
        - To N.M. Butler, 25 April 1944 (Box 1)
        - To George A. Finch, 25 April 1944 (Box 1)
        - To Malcolm Davis, 1944-1948 (8 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
        - To E.B. Sayre, 23 April 1945 9 July 1945 (2 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
        - To Alger Hiss, 9 May 1947 23 May 1947 (2 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Byrd, Richard E.
        - To N.M. Butler, 22 Dec 1936 (Box 1)
        - To Henry S. Haskell, Dec 1936 May 1937 (3 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Cantor, Eddie. To N.M. Butler, 13 Jan 1936 (Box 1)
      - Curie, Marie. To D'Estournelles de Constant, 10 Jan 1924 (Box 1)
      - Damrosch, Walter. To N.M. Butler, 2 Dec. 1937 (Box 1)
      - Dulles, John Foster
        - To Joseph E. Johnson, 20 Sept 1950 5 July 1951 (2 t.l.s. with related material) (Box 1)
      - Eden, Anthony.
        - To N.M. Butler, 27 August 1934 27 Nov 1945 (Box 1)
        - To Henry Haskell, 30 May 1938 (Box 1)
      - Einstein, Albert, 5 March 1947 29 Nov. 1947 (Box 1)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D. To Elwood M. Thompson, 22 June 1948 (Box 1)
      - Eisenhower, Milton S. To Howard Wilson, 26 March1951 (Box 1)
      - Ellis, Havelock, 3 April 1922 (Box 1)
      - Freud, Sigmund. Contract for "The Psycho-Analytic Problem of the War", 10 Oct. 1921 (Box 1)
      - Galsworthy, John.
        - To Henry S. Haskell, 23 Feb 1919 (Box 1)
        - 22 May 1919 (Box 1)
      - Garland, Hamlin
        - To N.M. Butler, 10 Jan, 22 Jan, 20, July 1919 (2 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
        - To William Sloane, 4 Oct 1921 (Box 1)
      - Herter, Christian A. To Jospeh E. Johnson, 20 Feb 1952 (Box 1)
      - Hoover, Herbert
        - 9 Dec 1925 (Box 1)
        - To N.M. Butler, 1925 1939 (2 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
        - To James B. Scott, 10 July 1926 (Box 1)
        - To James T. Sotwell, 19 Aug. 1950 (Box 1)
        - To Jospeh E. Johnson, 14 Sept 1950 (Box 1)
      - Howells, William Dean. To N.M. Butler, Feb. 1919 (2 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Hughes, Charles Evans. To Henry S. Haskell, 12 Aug. 1929 (Box 1)
      - Jesperson, Otto. To Henry S. Haskell, 6 September 1916 (Box 1)
      - Kennan, George. To Jospeh E. Johnson, 15 Jan 1952 (Box 1)
      - LaGuardia, Fiorello H, 15 Dec 1932 (Box 1)
      - Leacock, Stephen
        - To N.M. Butler, Jan-Feb 1919 (1 t.l.s., 2 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
        - To Henry S. Haskell, 13 Feb 1919 (Box 1)
      - Lie, Trygve Halvdan. To Howard E. Wilson, 2 March1949 (Box 1)
      - Lloyd George, David. To Henry S. Haskell, 29 Oct 1938 (Box 1)
      - MacDonald, James Ramsay. To N.M. Butler, Nov 1911 June and Nov 1925 (3 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - MacLeish, Archibald. To N.M. Butler, Feb and May 1942 (2 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Mann, Thomas, 30 Nov 1925 (Box 1)
      - Masaryk, Jan
        - To Henry S. Haskell, 1 Feb. 1939 (Box 1)
        - To N.M. Butler, 16 May 1939 (Box 1)
      - Masters, Edgar Lee. To N.M. Butler, Jan-March 1919 (4 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Matthews, Brander. To Henry S. Haskell, May 1919 (2 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Murray, Gilbert. To Joseph E. Johnson, 1 Nov 1950 (Box 1)
      - Myrdal, Gunnar. To Joseph E. Johnson, 4 July 1951 (Box 1)
      - Nkrumah, Kwame. To Joseph E. Johnson, 30 Jan 1952 (Box 1)
      - Noyes, Alfred. To N.M. Butler, Jan-Feb. 1919 (t.l.s., a.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Orlando, Vittorio Emanuele. To N.M. Butler, 25 July 1938 (Box 1)
      - Pearson, Lester B. To James Shotwell, 20 Oct 1952 (Box 1)
      - Pershing, John J. To N.M. Butler, 15 June 1938 (Box 1)
      - Pound, Ezra. To Henry S. Haskell, 7 Dec 1932 (Box 1)
        Letter must be consulted on microfilm (#81-6019).
      - Rickover, Hyman, 15 Feb 1931 (Box 1)
      - Rockefeller, John D. III. To Malcolm Davis, 12 Nov 1946 (Box 1)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson. To Malcolm Davis, 2 Feb 1942 (Box 1)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor. To Joseph E. Johnson, July 1950 July 1951 Dec 1951 (3 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D. To N.M. Butler, 5 Feb. 1929 2 Feb. 1930 (2 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Rusk, Dean. To Joseph E. Johnson, 1950-1951 (2 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
      - Spaak, Paul Henri. To Howard E. Wilson, 11 Jan. 1949 (Box 1)
      - Stanton, Theodore, 20 March 1921 (Box 1)
      - Stevenson, Adlai E.
        - To Malcom Davis, 9 May 1945 (Box 1)
        - To Alger Hiss, April -Oct 1947 (4 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
        - To Elwood Thompson, 18 March1948 (Box 1)
      - Stout, Rex
        - To James Shotwell, 4 June 1943 (Box 1)
        - To Malcom Davis, 11 Nov 1946 (Box 1)
      - Taft, William Howard
        - To Henry S. Haskell, 3 April 1918 (Box 1)
        - To CEIP, 14 June 1920 (Box 1)
      - Toynebee, Arnold J.
        - 2 Nov 1936 (Box 1)
        - To Henry S. Haskell, 10 Oct 1942 (Box 1)
      - Truman, Harry S. To Joseph E. Johnson and James T. Shotwell, 30 June 1950 (Box 1)
      - Wister, Owen
        - To N.M. Butler, 23 Jan 1919 25 Jan 1922 8 Feb 1922 (3 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
        - To William M. Sloane, 20 March 1922 (Box 1)
    - Subsubseries I.A.2. General correspondence, 1910-1952
      (108 vols, 4 boxes)
      Correspondence through 1936 is indexed unless otherwise noted. (Indices are available in RBML. Electronic versions of the indices are in preparation.)
      - 1910-1911 (Volume 402-407)
      - 1912 (Vol 409 missing and not indexed) (Volume 408-409)
      - 1913 (Vols 410-411 (1-1645) missing.) (Volume 410-412)
      - 1914 (Volume 413-415)
      - 1915 (Volume 416-418)
      - 1916 (Volume 419-420)
      - 1917 (Volume 421-424)
      - 1918 (Volume 425-429)
      - 1919 (Volume 430-433)
      - 1920 (Volume 434-436)
      - 1921 (Volume 437-439)
      - 1922 (Volume 440-442)
      - 1923 (Volume 443-446)
      - 1924 (Volume 447-450)
      - 1925 (Volume 451-454)
      - 1926 (Volume 455-459)
      - 1927 (Volume 460-464)
      - 1928 (Volume 465-468)
      - 1929 (Volume 469-472)
      - 1930 (Volume 473-477)
      - 1931 (Volume 478-482)
      - 1932 (Volume 483-488)
      - 1933 (Volume 489-494)
      - 1934 (Volume 495-500)
      - 1935 (Volume 501-505)
      - 1936 (Volume 506-509)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 2)
      - Canadian Institute of International Affairs, 1951 (Box 2)
      - Clough, Ernest, 1952 (Box 2)
      - Columbia University: (Box 3)
        - 1952 (Box 3)
        - Seminar on Peace, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Committee to Study the Organization of Peace, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Committee on Membership, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Council on Foreign Relatons:
        - 1952 (Box 3)
        - Angol-American Study Group, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Davis, Malcom, 1952 (See also I.H.6 and III.C.2.c.) (Box 3)
      - Denver, University of-Social Science Foundation, 1952 (Box 3)
      - DeRusset, Alan, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Ford Foundation, 1950-1952 (Box 3)
      - German Society for Studies in World Affairs (Gessellschaft fur Auslandskunde), 1952 (Box 3)
      - Institute of Pacific Relations, American, 1952 (Box 4)
      - Institute of World Affairs (New York City and the University of Utah), 1949-1950 (Box 4)
      - Mundt Bill, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
      - National Commttee for a Free Europe, 1951 (Box 4)
      - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1952 (Box 4)
      - State Department (U.S.)-National Conference on U.S. Foreign Policy, 1951 (Box 4)
      - Study Groups, 1952 (Box 4)
      - Trochet, Lucien-Building and Trades Union, Geneva, 1952 (Box 4)
      - United Nations-General Assembly, 1951 (Box 4)
      - United Nations Association, 1944 (Box 4)
      - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) (Box 4)
      - 1948-1952 (Box 4)
      - International Seminar on Teaching of History, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
      - VIP Letters (Box 4)
      - World Federation of UN Associations, 1948-1951 (Box 5)
      - Unsolicited Letters, 1915-1919 1934-1925 1930-1948 (Box 5)
    - Sub-subseries I.A.3: Minor (day-to-day) correspondence, 1911-1930
      (25 volumes)
      The volumes in this subseries are indexed. (Indices are available in RBML. Electronic versions of the indices are in preparation.)
      - 1910-1911 (Volume 512)
      - 1912 (Volume 513)
      - 1913 (Volume 514-515)
      - 1914 (Volume 516)
      - 1915 (Volume 517-518)
      - 1916 (Volume 519-520)
      - 1917 (Volume 521-523)
      - 1918 (Volume 524)
      - 1919 (Volume 525)
      - 1920 (Volume 526)
      - 1921 (Volume 527)
      - 1922 (Volume 528-529)
      - 1923 (Volume 530-531)
      - 1924 (Volume 532)
      - 1925 (Volume 533)
      - 1927 (Volume 534)
      - 1928-1930 (Volume 535-536)
    - Sub-subseries I.A.4: Individual Files, 1922-1948
      (3 boxes)
      - William Warner Bishop (Librarian, University of Michigan), 1922-1938 (Box 6)
        - 1922-1923 1926-1927 1929-1933
        - 1934-1938 (Box 7)
      - Louise W. Carnegie, 1924-1943 (Box 7)
      - William Miller Collier (Ambassador to Chile from United States), 1926-1930 (Box 7)
      - Lewis Einstein, 1927 (Box 7)
      - Manley O. Hudson (Professor of Law, Harvard University; Justice, International Court )
        - 1915-1932 (Box 7)
        - 1933-1945 (Box 8)
      - Edwin Mead, 1931 (Box 8)
    - Sub-subseries I.A 5: Crank Letter File, 1935-1949, (1 folder)
      - This file, in chronological order, is a sample of "crank" letters. (Box 8)
    - Sub-subseries I.A 6: Opinion Survey of 1925, (3 folders)
      - In 1925 the Endowment sent out form letters to important individuals all soliciting comments on the Endowment's work and recommendations for future fields of endeavor. This file (in chronological order by month of reply) contains the replies to the letter. (Box 8)
      - May -June (Box 8)
      - July -December (Box 9)
    - Sub-subseries I.A 7: Requests, 1923-1949
      (1 box) This subseries comprises a sample of requests for information and for literature that were received by the Endowment.
      - For information, 1923-1947 (Box 9)
      - For literature and speakers, 1925-1949 (Box 9)
  - Subseries I.B: Annual report materials, 1931-1949
    Each year the Endowment published a Yearbook containing the reports of the various divisions and financial statements for the previous year. These yearbooks were distributed gratis to the Endowment's designated depository libraries and to qualified individuals who requested copies from the Endowment.
    This subseries consists mostly of typescript versions of the reports that were included in the annuals. Most of these reports were submitted by the three divisions of the Endowment, the secretary's office, the treasurer, the investment committee, and the executive and finance committees of the Board of Trustees. The files for some years also include various special reports on particular projects or activities in which the Endowment was engaged; minutes from board and executive committee meetings; the Endowment's reports to the Carnegie Corporation, which supported the Endowment financially; and photographs.
    - 1931-1935 1937-1939 (Box 9)
    - 1940-1947 (Box 10)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 11)
  - Subseries I.C: Board of Trustees, 1910-1943
    (12 boxes)
    This subseries contains correspondence regarding the activities and policies of the Board of Trustees and copies of the letters, reports, publications, memoranda, resolutions, meeting agendas, and proposals sent to the trustees by the Endowment.
    The material covers various issues including upcoming meetings, the selection of new trustees, the status of particular initiatives, and the organization of the Endowment and its component parts. (For the Green Cover Reports received by the Trustees see Series I.N. Reports for Trustee Information.)Subseries I.C. is organized into the following subseries:1. General
    2. Meetings
    3. Executive committee
    4. Trustee files
    - Sub-subseries I.C.1: General, 1913-1948
      - 1913 1915 1925-1929 1935-1942 (Box 11)
      - 1943-1948 (Box 12)
    - Sub-subseries I.C.2: Meetings-Verbatim transcripts, 1910-1943